<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CFW STEM Committee</title>
    <description>Group of highly motivated male, female, and ally students at the undergraduate and graduate levels focused on improving the status and representation of women in science, technology, engineering, and math fields at the University of Tennessee.
</description>
    <link>http://cfwstem.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cfwstem.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:52:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to our Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there. We are the Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM) Committee with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cfw.utk.edu/&quot;&gt;Commission for Women&lt;/a&gt; (CFW) at the University of Tennessee. 
Established during the Fall semester of 2014, we planned and hosted the &lt;a href=&quot;/symposium/2015/02/13/first-annual-women-in-stem-research-symposium.html&quot;&gt;first-ever Women in STEM Research Symposium&lt;/a&gt; as our inaugural event. 
This year, in addition to hosting the 2nd annual symposium, we will be: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;establishing a new interdisciplinary mentorship program that will be open to both undergraduate and graduate students here at UT. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;focusing more heavily on our fundamental initiative to collect and disseminate data and information on the status and representation of undergraduate, graduate, and faculty women in STEM fields at UT. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim to serve as a campus-wide support system that fosters an environment of interdisciplinary engagement while providing networking and professional development opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our committee, which consists of both men, women, and allies at the undergraduate and graduate student levels, is a group of motivated individuals dedicated to promoting diversity and equity on campus and within the academic and professional research communities. 
If you have a passion for equity, diversity, or promoting awareness on women’s issues, we want to work with you! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, join our mailing list or check back here for more updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our website is currently under construction … thank you for visiting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cfwstem.github.io/welcome/2015/10/19/welcome-to-our-new-website.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cfwstem.github.io/welcome/2015/10/19/welcome-to-our-new-website.html</guid>
        
        <category>welcome</category>
        
        
        <category>welcome</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Annual Women in STEM Research Symposium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently in the process of organizing the 2016 Women in STEM Research Symposium next Spring. Look below for details from this past Spring’s Symposium!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conference-description&quot;&gt;Conference Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The symposium is a FREE, full day professional conference with undergraduate and graduate poster &amp;amp; oral sessions, a plenary presentation given by Dr. Claudia Rawn (Director, UTK Center for Materials Processing), a question &amp;amp; answer panel of STEM faculty &amp;amp; staff from the university, Oak Ridge National Lab, and local industry, AND a STEM Student Org Expo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registration&quot;&gt;Registration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men and women are invited to attend! Female undergraduate and graduate student researchers are invited to submit an abstract; remember, space is limited! If you would like to volunteer to help out at the conference OR would like to host a table at the Expo, please use the same registration link above or contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#102;&amp;#119;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#109;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#107;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#102;&amp;#119;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#109;&amp;#064;&amp;#117;&amp;#116;&amp;#107;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the results of our faculty judges, the best poster and best talk will receive a FREE PARKING PASS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see below for a more detailed schedule of the day’s events and the call for abstracts. For reminders and updates, follow the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/utkcfwstem&quot;&gt;CFW STEM Committee on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/utkcfwstem&quot;&gt;@utkcfwstem&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Details&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;8:00 a.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Registration, Coffee &amp;amp; Networking, Poster Session A Setup&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;9:30 a.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Welcoming Remarks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;10:00 a.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Oral &amp;amp; Poster Session A&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:30 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lunch break, Poster Session B Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;12:30 p.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Plenary Speaker: Dr. Claudia Rawn&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;1:30 p.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Oral &amp;amp; Poster Session B&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;3:00 p.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;STEM Faculty &amp;amp; Staff Q&amp;amp;A Panel&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;4:30 p.m.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Award Ceremony &amp;amp; Closing Remarks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;call-for-abstracts&quot;&gt;Call for Abstracts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT DEADLINE EXTENDED! Poster and oral abstracts now due FRIDAY, APRIL 3RD by 5 PM!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;poster-sessions&quot;&gt;Poster Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;session-description&quot;&gt;Session Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poster sessions will allow for the informal discussion of scholarly research being done by undergraduate and graduate women in science, technology, engineering and math fields from the University of Tennessee. Posters will be assigned to one of two 90-minute poster sessions (Session A – morning, Session B – afternoon) based on department (field) and specific research area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;submission-format&quot;&gt;Submission Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poster session abstracts are limited to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Title (20 words)
Author(s) name, Institution(s)
Abstract, not to exceed 300 words, that briefly addresses the following topics:
Overall research goal, hypotheses, and/or background
Methodology, experimental design, instrumentation, and/or techniques used to collect/analyze data
Results, discussion, and/or conclusions
Note: Once you have submitted your abstract, you may not edit or resubmit. Only one abstract may be submitted per student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selection-criteria&quot;&gt;Selection Criteria&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event that more students submit abstracts than can be accommodated in the University Center space, abstracts will be evaluated based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the title accurate, broadly descriptive, and communicate the importance of the research?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the work grounded in a larger body of theory or research?item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the description of the research approach clear?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the abstract communicate the originality and/or innovation of the work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the abstract organized well and concise?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the rubric that the judges will use to evaluate your poster presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;poster-preparation&quot;&gt;Poster Preparation:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posters should be printed on flexible, matte or laminated paper and should not exceed a maximum of 48 inches wide x 36 inches tall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posters should be hung in University Center Room 223/224 according to the number you receive when you check in at the registration table on April 18th. 
You will have access to the room at least 1 hour prior to your session.
Push pins and technical equipment for hanging posters will be provided.
Neither tables nor power sources will be provided.
We recommend you bring business cards or post contact information near your poster in the event that someone would like to continue your discussion after the session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oral-sessions&quot;&gt;Oral Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;session-description-1&quot;&gt;Session Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PowerPoint-based oral sessions will allow for a formal presentation of scholarly research being done by undergraduate and graduate women in science, technology, engineering and math fields from the University of Tennessee. Presentations will be assigned to 1 of 4 oral sessions (Session A.1, A.2 – morning, or Session B.1, B.2 – afternoon) along with 4 other speakers, for a total of 5 presentations each session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;submission-format-1&quot;&gt;Submission Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oral session abstracts are limited to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Title (20 words)
Author(s) name, Institution(s)
Abstract, not to exceed 300 words, that briefly addresses the following topics:
Overall research goal, hypotheses, and/or background
Methodology, experimental design, instrumentation, and/or techniques used to collect/analyze data
Results, discussion, and/or conclusions
 Note: Once you have submitted your abstract, you may not edit or resubmit. Only one abstract may be submitted per student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selection-criteria-1&quot;&gt;Selection Criteria&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event that more students submit abstracts than can be accommodated during each session’s allotted time, abstracts will be evaluated based on the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the title accurate, broadly descriptive, and communicate the importance of the research?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the work grounded in a larger body of theory or research?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the description of the research approach clear?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the abstract communicate the originality and/or innovation of the work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the abstract organized well and concise?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the rubric that the judges will use to evaluate your oral presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;presentation-preparation&quot;&gt;Presentation Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentations should be no more than 15 minutes in length and there will be 5 minutes for discussion and changeover to the next speaker. Please be considerate of other speakers and the audience by staying within your allotted time. Session chairs will help you hold to the allotted time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic files must be prepared using the formats listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operating System: Media should be PC-formatted or Mac OS X&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug-Ins: Quicktime 7, Windows Media Player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each session room is equipped with a Windows PC and a Mac connection capability, a laptop, and a LCD projector. Please bring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;your presentation on a flash drive or your computer with the file saved to the desktop for quick access. A local monitor is also provided and will mirror what the audience sees (Presenter View is not supported). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;at least two copies of your presentation to the session in case there is a problem with one of the files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers should report to University Center Room 225 or 226 at least 10 minutes prior to the session start time based on the information provided to you when you check in at the Registration table on April 18th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://cfwstem.github.io/symposium/2015/02/13/first-annual-women-in-stem-research-symposium.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cfwstem.github.io/symposium/2015/02/13/first-annual-women-in-stem-research-symposium.html</guid>
        
        <category>symposium</category>
        
        
        <category>symposium</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
